<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 11:26:04 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 11:26:04 -0700</lastBuildDate>

    
      <item>
        <title>Fiesta</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/18212-fiesta</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <author></author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;1:00 pm&lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Brigg&amp;rsquo;s Office&lt;br /&gt;
Today is my niece&amp;rsquo;s birthday. Right now is the party. They rented a bounce house again. My brother told me this year they&amp;rsquo;re getting a magician, and maybe even hiring one of those people who show up to the party and prance around in a funny costume. I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I won&amp;rsquo;t be there. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m here, it being the kid&amp;rsquo;s birthday and all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[REDACTED]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Well, yes. Technically, I was invited. But it was one of those obligatory invitations where you&amp;rsquo;re invited just because whoever invited you would feel bad if they didn&amp;rsquo;t. We&amp;rsquo;re still family after all. No one expected me to respond; it was a courtesy really.&lt;br /&gt;
 I still make time to see my niece when I can, when her mother is out of town of course. I can&amp;rsquo;t say I blame her. Hell, I&amp;rsquo;d be upset with me too. Not that I think it&amp;rsquo;s my fault. I don&amp;rsquo;t. Full disclosure, I think if you&amp;rsquo;d cut the blame into a pie she&amp;rsquo;d have the bigger slice. Not that I&amp;rsquo;d ever say that out loud. Outside of here, I mean. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[REDACTED]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[REDACTED]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I just say? I don&amp;rsquo;t want to talk it about it. It&amp;rsquo;s as embarrassing as it is tragic. I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to let sleeping dogs lie, thank you very much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[REDACTED]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright fine. I surrender. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk. This is me applauding you. Happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[REDACTED]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like this. My brother, Anthony, he&amp;rsquo;s a great dad, but he&amp;rsquo;s a sucker for his little girl. And, Becca, she&amp;rsquo;s a good kid and all but she&amp;rsquo;s a princess because of it. It&amp;rsquo;s the kid&amp;rsquo;s birthday, and she&amp;rsquo;s turning five years old. She&amp;rsquo;s in kindergarten at this point, so it&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;d call a &amp;ldquo;big deal.&amp;rdquo; My brother Anthony goes all out like he does every year, except this time it&amp;rsquo;s more than usual. We&amp;rsquo;re talking about a bounce house, balloon animals, face painting, cotton candy. You name it. The spoiled kind of works. Anthony gets this girl two cakes. Two. Just in case one of these rugrats doesn&amp;rsquo;t like chocolate. Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like chocolate cake? And don&amp;rsquo;t get me started about how many kids my brother invited. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[REDACTED]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I don&amp;rsquo;t like kids. I mean, I don&amp;rsquo;t, but it was the amount of them there that got to me. It was like the goddamn children of the corn. It was just what you&amp;rsquo;d probably call over-stimulation. That&amp;rsquo;s the word...&lt;br /&gt;
 So anyway, we cut the cake, well, both cakes I should say, and then Anthony decides it&amp;rsquo;s time to bring out the pi&amp;ntilde;ata. This thing looks like a Disney princess with a skin condition the way the paper is fraying off the cardboard. I don&amp;rsquo;t know which exact princess it was, I don&amp;rsquo;t have kids, but these children go nuts over it. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen anything like it. You would have thought they were on the brink of a riot the way these kids were acting. Just berserk.&lt;br /&gt;
Becca&amp;rsquo;s the birthday girl, so she&amp;rsquo;s the first up at bat. They blindfold her, and my brother gives her a Louisville Slugger that&amp;rsquo;s almost as big as she is to break open the pinata with. And remember, Becca just turned five. There&amp;rsquo;s no way she can break this thing open with her eyes, let alone do it blindfolded. She can hardly lift the bat. So she tries and she fails, and the next kid comes up and he fails, and on and on it goes. Kids dragging the bat toward the pinata hanging above them, and rarely making contact. They didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother blindfolding them by the end. &lt;br /&gt;
Of course, eventually these kids just want the candy. Nobody cares who brains the princess, so they decide to elect a champion. &lt;br /&gt;
Now, I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, I had a couple of drinks in me at this point, so I more or less volunteered myself for the job as opposed to a more democratic form of selection.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lsquo;Get it over with,&amp;rsquo; Anthony tells me, &amp;lsquo;Do it without the blindfold,&amp;rsquo; he says. And I think, &amp;ldquo;no.&amp;rdquo; Because if there&amp;rsquo;s one thing I hate it&amp;rsquo;s being told what to do. &lt;br /&gt;
So now I&amp;rsquo;m blindfolded, and I asked, well more like demanded to be spun around in circles. I make a big display of it. I put on a show. After I&amp;rsquo;m good and spun they gave me a shove towards the pi&amp;ntilde;ata and I took my first swing.&lt;br /&gt;
CRACK!&lt;br /&gt;
Direct hit. The bat vibrated in my hands. I knew I put a dent in this thing, so I swung again. &lt;br /&gt;
CRACK!&lt;br /&gt;
This time the crowd goes wild. I hear bits of candy skitter across the ground, and I think this is it. Right? My hero moment. I am going to break this motherfucker wide open. I planted my feet, I cocked this bat back like I was Babe Ruth about to knock one out of Fenway park.&lt;br /&gt;
My sister-in-laws mother, for only god knows why, chooses this precise moment to venture across the yard for another glass of wine. You following this?&lt;br /&gt;
 And I can I can only assume that she wasn&amp;rsquo;t paying attention, because she as she&amp;rsquo;s saying something about the lovely weather we&amp;rsquo;re having today she walks right in front of the princess.&lt;br /&gt;
CRACK!&lt;br /&gt;
The rest is history. Paramedics said there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything anybody could have done differently. Pretend you&amp;rsquo;re me. Now what do you do in a situation like that? I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s not like you can just take off. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[REDACTED]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I found a corner, pulled up a chair, and nursed a beer. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of a better option at the time. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell you a better alternative looking back. &lt;br /&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s funny; I feel all of the things you would expect me to feel. Guilt, remorse, self-hatred, pity, the list goes on, and I feel all of that everyday. But you know what really gets me? When I think about what it must have been like to be her. It keeps me awake at night. I think of what it would be like to be her in those last moments; watching this drunken fool embarrassing himself in front of a bunch of children. I imagine her sipping a glass of wine until it&amp;rsquo;s gone, watching her kid and her kid&amp;rsquo;s kid, lives that she helped construct. I imagine her being proud. Happy. And maybe she thinks to herself &amp;ldquo;if this isn&amp;rsquo;t great, I just don&amp;rsquo;t know what is.&amp;rdquo; And maybe as all of this is happening she realizes that her glass is empty, and, without giving it much thought at all, she decides to help herself to a refill. I imagine her head being full of thoughts I&amp;rsquo;ll never know, orbiting her brain like a satellite in an infinite stream of thoughts, just as complex as the ones I have in my own, and then all at once, nothing at all. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mother</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/171211-mother</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <author></author>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;photo-grid&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;half-left&quot;&gt;How long has it been since you were her. You can
handle the truth when itdoesn&amp;rsquo;t sting. doesn&amp;rsquo;t sting.
  Here she is. Exactly half of you. Bright eyes, tiny feet, never still, dressed
  in a violet sundress and silly shoes. This is your new heartbeat. Have you ever
  loved anything this small or this much?&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;half-right&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/365days.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long has it been since you were her. You can handle the truth when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sting.&lt;br /&gt;
Here she is. Exactly half of you. Bright eyes, tiny feet, never still, dressed
in a violet sundress and silly shoes. This is your new heartbeat. Have you ever
loved anything this small or this much?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is a big day. The first in a succession of many. She will leave you like a bird departing from the nest. Taking flight for the first time, and joining the ranks of other chickadees blindly entering the world. Here is the list of necessities. Pencils and crayons and scissors and glue. Double check them twice to ensure nothing is missing.&lt;br /&gt;
Look at the way she is. Pause to admire her growth. She models a backpack in the mirror, twists to examine it from all angles. Here she is laughing. Always laughing. This is her: The most personal extension of you. On the day she was born, you took her home and refused to remove her from your side. She slept beside you as you stroked her hair and placed delicate kisses on her skin. And for the first time you felt a certain bitterness in how time seems to pass faster the tighter you try and hold onto it.&lt;br /&gt;
 Be proud. Your beautiful baby has matured into a beautiful child. She is consumed by joy and all things good.&lt;br /&gt;
You are her protector. Nothing exists that you wouldn’t do for her. Her words are ceaseless in production, yet you care about all she has to say. This isn’t duty; it’s devotion. You have volunteered to prepare her for the world and to try and make sense of it. You will teach her to be good, but you will not teach her how to think. Allow her to make mistakes on her own, and she will be stronger because of it.&lt;br /&gt;
Tomorrow she will no longer be yours alone. She will be a light whose brightness you will share with the world. Time will make her sprout taller. She will lose teeth and replace them with others. She will outgrow these new clothes, beliefs, and the friends she has yet to make. It will not be entirely pleasant. Nothing ever is. She will develop an attitude, and opinions that stray from your own. Time will make her older, and not always wiser. There will be boys. Or girls. All kinds of each. These too will pass until there is only one, and it is time to begin a family of her own. But that time is not now. &lt;br /&gt;
Right now she is yours. How long has it been since you were her. You can handle the truth when it doesn’t sting. You have a past of your own. A past filled with people you chose to love on purpose. And now, what seems clear to you is that it is possible to love someone so permanently that it can never be undone. &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Almond Joy</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/171211-almond-joy</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <author></author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Been seeing flags hung at half mast more and more these day, and I guess that makes sense. I don't mean to sound like a pessimist, I just think when you have a specific kind of experience it's the way you tend to see things. I've been a cop, for what, damn near 30 years now. It'll be 30 next June. Signed up right after they handed me my diploma and never looked back. I can't deny that there are a few bad apples, but speaking from my own experience, most cops are decent enough folks. I think what people don't realize, and what most of us don't like to talk about too much, is how we see the things most people don't. It&amp;rsquo;s a job not everyone is capable of doing. Some guys drop out in under a year, and none of us can really blame him. Being a cop can fill your head with some heavy shit. Most of us don't like talking about the things they're trying to forget.&lt;br /&gt;
Best way I can describe it is by saying most calls are like meals. You might be able to recall the specifics for a couple days, but after enough time passes it's just something you ate once upon a time. Of course, there are some meals you remember for months, or even years after you've had them. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s because it was a damn good meal and you're glad you ate it. With calls you remember, it's the opposite more or less. The first call I remember, really remember, was about a couple of kids coming home from prom. This stupid kid drinks a bit too much and gets brave because he's a stupid kid, and ends up spread out on the highway like butter on toast. And of course, he takes his date with him. Back then I was a stupid kid too, meaning I was just a few years older. &lt;br /&gt;
I showed up and end up having to make the report. I lost my dinner on the side of the highway, and a couple of the senior officers took a few jabs at me. Making jokes about me losing my appetite. Back then I didn't understand it. Why they were making jokes, I mean. Nowadays it makes sense. Because often times it's a choice between laughing or crying. And when you've spent enough time on the force and watched people you shared a car with eat their own guns, often times it makes a hell of a lot more sense to laugh.&lt;br /&gt;
When I think about it about it now the images of the two kids isn't quite as clear as you might think, and maybe that's for the best. Like any memory there's an idea of what you remember, and the reality of the way things were. What I do remember, clearer than any memory I've had, is the sounds the girl's mother made when she showed up to the scene of the accident. Sounds like that you don't forget. Sometimes when I'm alone I can still hear it. That night I picked up the bottle and never managed to find a way to put it down.&lt;br /&gt;
Some cases just get filed in that part of your brain where the bad things you want to forget go, and that's all part of the job. It's what you know you're signing up for without knowing what you're signing up for. And that's fine. I've made as much peace as I can with it. Every now and again you get a call you wish was picked up by someone else. You see something that gets stored to that bad part of your brain. Something that reminds you why you picked up the bottle in the first place.&lt;br /&gt;
In the force we have this thing called the &amp;quot;Almond Joy Theory,&amp;quot; for when things happen that you can't quite explain. Almond Joy used to have this slogan that went &amp;quot;Sometimes you feel like nut, sometimes you don't.&amp;quot; It's something we used to say to make each other laugh, because that's what we did when we needed to. Calling perps &amp;quot;Almond Joys,&amp;quot; you know?&lt;br /&gt;
I got call on the radio, and what I'm supposed to do is head over to this address to investigate a domestic dispute. A domestic dispute is the words they use. So I buckle up, and my partner buckles up, and what we do is we head over the address they tell us to check out. All of this is protocol right? We head over, take some notes, and every once and awhile we have to put someone in handcuffs.&lt;br /&gt;
We show up to the house and this lady comes running out the door, and she's going on out about this and that, and how about this son of a bitch had it coming. And did I mention, this woman, she's covered in blood. She's wearing this white dress with this big red spot on it lookin' like the damn flag of Japan. And her face is splattered with the stuff like someone had been swinging a brush dipped in red paint at her. And all of this looks pretty bad, so what I do is I tell my partner&amp;#9148;&amp;#9148;who by the way isn't even out of the car yet&amp;#9148;&amp;#9148;that he needs to stay with her. Take a statement, and that'll I'll go inside to see what&amp;rsquo;s what.&lt;br /&gt;
I got inside the house and the place was more or less a pig sty. There were old plates with rancid food on them, and it stunk bad enough to gag a maggot, and I'm already starting to piece together what happened. A domestic dispute, right? Wife gets upset at the husband and does something stupid and now we're here trying to figure out just exactly what that stupid thing was. I walked around, took notes, and surveyed the scene, before I turn into the kitchen and see the husband.&lt;br /&gt;
By the time I got there the flies had already found him. He had a hole in the side of his head the size of a dime and he's lying in this growing puddle of blood right there on the ground. His mouth was hung open like he was about to say something. Little rivers of blood are streaked down the side of the wall above the stove, and there were these fresh groceries just sitting there on the counter coated with blood.&lt;br /&gt;
In the corner of the room was the daughter. She's no older than six or seven years old, and she just stood there staring at what used to be her daddy. And if she was feeling any kind of way she ain't showing it. She just stood there staring dead eyed at the body, and the puddle of blood, and when the puddle got close enough, what she did was she took a step back.&lt;br /&gt;
The first thing I did is get her the hell out of there, because that's something she doesn't need to have in the bad part of her brain. I picked her up, and get her outside, and I try tried talking to her, only she&amp;rsquo;s not saying much which given the circumstances, who can blame her, you know? And my partner and I call for backup, and the backup comes, and we put up the tape, and they're taking pictures, and so on and so forth.&lt;br /&gt;
What my partner tells me is that the wife came home with groceries that the husband told her to get, and he decided to get a mouth about the milk. Because, as she told it, he wanted regular milk and what the wife bought was almond. So he started slapping her around, which of course, she's used to and started calling her bad names that I don't quite feel like repeating, and when the daughter came into see what the commotion is about he started giving it to her too. And of course, this had been going on for years, and of course she had never said anything because she's so afraid of this man she loves for some reason. &lt;br /&gt;
But now it&amp;rsquo;s different. Because now it&amp;rsquo;s about her child who&amp;#9148;&amp;#9148;despite everything&amp;#9148;&amp;#9148;is the only person she loves more than him.&lt;br /&gt;
 So what she did is she ran upstairs for the pistol, and when she came back down she put a bullet right in his skull. And of course, the daughter saw the whole thing. What my partner told me is that she did this to protect her, because beating them isn't the only thing he was doing to them, of course. And what? We're left with no other option but to put her in handcuffs and throw her in the back of the car. And neither us blamed her, but of course, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t say that. &lt;br /&gt;
And now this little girl, who woke up in the morning with both parents, is going to bed that same night with no parents. Meanwhile, I got one of the deputy's in my ear talking about how he can't wait to get home to get himself a drink, and of course I hate myself for agreeing with him. So what we do is we make jokes.&lt;br /&gt;
Because often times it's a choice between laughing or crying.&lt;br /&gt;
So what my partner said to me is if his wife brought home almond milk, he figures he would have shot her first. And what I said back is there's no use crying over spilled milk.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stand</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/171114-Stand</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <author></author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here you are. You are here because your friends wanted you to be. Pleaded with accusations of you wasting your youth, of growing old and becoming a reflection of your parents. Here everyone is young and careless and bold. They come here to behave this way and forget why they came. &lt;br /&gt;
 Push through the gates that separate in from out. Join the bodies. Varied shapes and shades and organs and origins. All of them like water. Constant in a state of flux. You join the rhythm, move to sanguine sounds with the other bodies, tightly packed like a serpent&amp;rsquo;s coil. Your friends like the way you move. The jagged motions, stiff hips and limbs. No natural instincts. It makes them feel more content with themselves. &lt;br /&gt;
 But you are you. You are not without your merits. You are here because your friends wanted you to be. Your company lifts their spirits. You are pleasant to be around. They enjoy your voice. Your words inspire laughter and love and affection.&lt;br /&gt;
 Here they serve potions that borrow happiness from tomorrow. It affects your friends in different ways. Makes them laugh or cry, and sometimes both at once. You have been known to drink more than you should and to make impulsive decisions based on previous ones. You have given yourself a limit you know you&amp;rsquo;ll exceed, and tomorrow when you wake up you will beg your body for forgiveness. Trade plastic for more. Share it with your friends. You&amp;rsquo;ve been here before. More than you would care to know. &lt;br /&gt;
The restroom is a pit stop for all. There are toilets people have suddenly forgotten how to use, and the floor is somehow entirely wet. You will keep a mental checklist of everything you touch with your hands before rinsing them and discovering both the soap and paper dispensers are empty. &lt;br /&gt;
Wipe your hands on your jeans. Pass time talking to strangers. Collect details you won&amp;rsquo;t mind forgetting. Some people smoke when they drink and you are not proud to be among them. There&amp;rsquo;s a man outside whose posture is slouched and passive. You target him for asking. He gives you one and a light, and you apologize for bothering him. Lie and say that you are a faithful smoker of whatever brand is being offered, and then bond over your fabricated common ground. Command him to have a good night as you slowly disengage. &lt;br /&gt;
For you, smoking is not a social activity. It is a time to lean, to collect thoughts and to assess your own sobriety on a numerical scale. If you allow yourself to be honest, you enjoy how you must look. &lt;br /&gt;
You are a reflection of your parents. Your parents smoked, and their parents before them. Smoking reminds you of a time before you. An era of the Malboro Men and Joe Camels, Marlon Brando, and Audrey Hepburn poised with a slender cigarette holder resting against seraphic cheekbones, classically beautiful and transcending time. The cigarette in your hand burns down to an ember. Kiss it goodbye and flick it away. &lt;br /&gt;
Inside, your friends are being more of themselves. They sit closer than normal, and lean in to speak with loose arms wrapped around each other&amp;rsquo;s necks and waists. It affects them all differently. For one friend, it robs her of her balance. It turns her limbs into rubber, and encourages her to ascend to new heights on wavering limbs. Another forgets his checking account is measured in numbers and becomes emboldened to bring it closer to zero in an almost competitive way. &lt;br /&gt;
Look around you. A boulder-shaped man dressed in all black directs the flow of traffic, determining who is fit to enter. The room is filled nearly to capacity. Glasses filled to the brim. An assortment of colors. And music that compels movement without consent. Everyone knows the words, and competes to sing them the loudest. There&amp;rsquo;s a reverse-congo line of people, shoulder to shoulder, pressed against a wooden counter. &lt;br /&gt;
And women. Women who have prepared themselves to be here with practiced motions of applying powders with brushes. Their skin is smooth as glass, a vaguely creamy complexion, some with wing-tipped lashes and an array of metal rings and jewelry. Tight clothing intended to complement their assets, and heels that add inches to their height, and announce their approach and departure. There&amp;rsquo;s an elegance in the way they move. Like ribbons in a soft breeze, delicate and intentional. &lt;br /&gt;
And men. Spindly men, thick-armed, burly men, boisterous, and effeminate men. So many men. More than you knew existed. They hang on the women like shadows on a planet with five suns. Closer than comfortable, leaning in with inquisitions, and touching them at place near the end of their spine. The men are largely predatory, but the women are not all unresponsive. Some touches are returned. Other men are disregarded entirely. Some women assume the role of the predator themselves. They will not be preyed upon. &lt;br /&gt;
All of the people you came with are occupied by friends or acquaintances. Absorb what&amp;rsquo;s around you, all of the dim possibilities. Your eyes meet the eyes of another. The gaze lingers like a silver wire strained between each of your bodies. The gaze does not stray with fluttering lashes to either side. Alcohol is a double-edged sword when it comes to seduction. Everything is a balance. An Aristotelian mean. &lt;br /&gt;
Here you are. It&amp;rsquo;s time. Time for you to make your move. Now or probably never. Don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself think about it. Thinking has only provided you with excuses not to do something, and the only things you tend to regret are the things you don&amp;rsquo;t do. You commit to the act of doing without thinking of what you would like to do. When the time comes to say something, what you say is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; That&amp;rsquo;s the best you&amp;rsquo;ve got, but it&amp;rsquo;s good enough. The stranger extends a hand in an invitation to touch, and become no longer strangers. Get to know one another. Collect details you&amp;rsquo;ll try not to forget. Tell them about you. The good and the not-so-bad. When girls flirt they touch. When boys flirt they touch. You are now both touching each other. &lt;br /&gt;
 Past the tangles of people, across the varied shapes, your friends are reunited. You look back and find them nodding their heads, raising chins and single eyebrows. From this distance it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to say whether or not they are supportive, but you have decided that it does not matter. When the lights turn on they kill the music. People gather belongings and join the migration to the exit in what looks like a marching group of unstable penguins.&lt;br /&gt;
 Outside you pull this person close to you. You let your hands linger on their body, and suggest you end the night in the same location. That&amp;rsquo;s when you do it. You pull them closer. You shut your eyes and commit to the action. Your lips touch then spread open to receive the other. Supple tongues twist, swirl and curl together. Your mouths taste like tobacco and tequila. It&amp;rsquo;s wet, and faintly spongy. The idea of a stranger&amp;rsquo;s tongue in your mouth offends you, but right now this feels good. It works for you. &lt;br /&gt;
 Cars are lined up at the curb in an enormous chain of colored light. You stumble over to someone smoking and ask for a smoke. He gives it to you, and you tell your acquaintance that you only do this when you&amp;rsquo;ve been drinking. Take their hand in yours. Feel it. It&amp;rsquo;s cold and bony and rests limp in your palm. Doors open and swallow up passengers waiting at the curb. The car pulls free from the chain, escorting them away, and another car replaces the link. This other person uses their phone to order your own.&lt;br /&gt;
 It&amp;rsquo;s cold out. Your breath turns to steam when you breath. Use this as an excuse to get closer. Huddle for warmth. How long has it been since you were this close to someone. Contact. This is nice. You consider that this person enjoys touching you as much as you enjoy touching them, and you decide that this is also nice. Your car pulls into the chain and you find yourselves climbing in on either side. The driver speaks to you in an accent neither one of you can identify and chews on neon-green gum. He offers you water and escorts you away from the crowd. &lt;br /&gt;
 Back at home you lead both of you though the door that separates in from out. Your personal fortress. A chipped wooden table with water stains in the shape of a ring, an abandoned sock only halfway under the couch, and wine glasses in the sink with little pools of burgundy above the stem. No home is always clean. All of this is an expression of you.&lt;br /&gt;
 Take them past this. Past the living room through the barren halls into your room. Your private quarters. And now they guide you to the bed. You become a victim of your own instincts. Something primal seizes you as you involve yourself. Give yourself to this familiar dance. The poetry of an ancient language in motion. Squeezing skin, fragile fingernails, and flexing hands flailing, tracing outlines and seizing fabric to rip away from nubile bodies. &lt;br /&gt;
 Here you are. &lt;br /&gt;
 The altar and the offering. Discovering and devouring each other. This isn&amp;rsquo;t love, but it is for now. Here you are. You are here because you want to be. The two of you are barely more than strangers, but for now you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ghosts</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/171114-Ghosts</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <author></author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
Most of my problems come from being an Irish Catholic. Being an Irish Catholic means that you&amp;rsquo;re dealt a specific set of cards at birth, and it isn&amp;rsquo;t the kind of hand you&amp;rsquo;d go all in on. One card guarantees you have an overwhelmingly limited emotional capacity, which amounts to a free pass when it comes to dealing with anything or anyone on an emotional level. When confronted with a problem, if you&amp;rsquo;re Irish, you can ignore it and people will pretty much look the other way. I think my grandfather maxed out on what he could feel as a person by the age of 11, and the apple doesn&amp;rsquo;t tend to fall too far from the tree. &lt;br /&gt;
 If there&amp;rsquo;s anything I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about Americans, it&amp;rsquo;s that they deal with most of their problems with escapism usually in the form of television or a chemical inebriant. And it must be the luck of the Irish that I was born here in the States. It&amp;rsquo;s the part of me that was raised American that is dependent on escapism as a coping mechanism, and it&amp;rsquo;s the Irish Catholic part of me takes that and runs with it. See, part of your identity is reliant on how much you can drink in a single sitting while watching a sports game. And if you&amp;rsquo;re a Mick from New England you love the Red Sox more than you love the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit combined. I&amp;rsquo;ve found this belief to be both truer and more wonderful the older I&amp;rsquo;ve become; praise the Lord! &lt;br /&gt;
 My dad couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more of a stereotype if he tried. He had this thing he would do where he would come home, drink, and then proceed to watch sports for hours without acknowledging the existence of anyone else. He feared intimacy in a way he probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t ever be willing to articulate, and he built walls around himself so high that the only person who could see over them was my mother if she stood on her metaphorical toes. I used to say that my father was a piece of furniture that came with the house when we bought it. My mom found this to be humorous. My father did not.&lt;br /&gt;
 My dad wasn&amp;rsquo;t a bad guy. He just wasn&amp;rsquo;t interested in being a parent. Being a dad who was willing to teach his kids about things just didn&amp;rsquo;t compute. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t in his coding. He believed that his fatherly duties began and ended with paying for groceries and the mortgage, and he may have smacked me from time to time for reasons I can&amp;rsquo;t say were unreasonable. The guy certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the running for any Father of the Year awards, but he was my father, and he was there &amp;#9148;&amp;#9148;until he wasn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;#9148;&amp;#9148; and I loved him for that. &lt;br /&gt;
Right now I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in my father&amp;rsquo;s office thinking on a memory I can barely remember. The calendar reads August 17th, 2012, and my mother is away on vacation. There&amp;rsquo;s a faint hum of passing cars as they drift off into the night to unknown destinations. The illumination of the television is the only light in our world. A sportscaster informs us that the Red Sox lead the Cubs by two runs here at the bottom of the eighth. We sip scotch on the rocks and smoke indoors. I mirror his posture. Shoes on, feet kicked up resting on the coffee table, we kiss flaming cigarettes, and let thoughts wander to the rhythm of the game. Here, time is irrelevant. Everything and nothing is temporary. Spectral streams of smoke twist and bend in the light as they dissolve into thin clouds making us appear as ghosts.&lt;br /&gt;
 The tip of his cigarette is a glowing charcoal he offers to the ashtray. He washes smoke down with a drink.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Hey kid. I want to ask you something,&amp;rdquo; he says.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Then ask.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll think I&amp;rsquo;m mad.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;I already think you&amp;rsquo;re mad,&amp;rdquo; I reply.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Fair enough.&amp;rdquo; He takes a drag, and caches the ash. &amp;ldquo;What do you think of the past?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;What do you mean?&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;The past. Your own history. What do you think of it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a shame.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re drunk.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Not drunk enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a shame.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;It is,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;What are your thoughts on the matter? You know, specifically.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know, Dad. What do you want me to say? The past is the past. It&amp;rsquo;s part of who you are, I guess, and I think sometimes people have a hard time remembering it&amp;rsquo;s not the present.&amp;rdquo; I breathe smoke out one side of my mouth. &amp;ldquo;Hey the Yankees are going to be in town in a couple of weeks. We should see if we can&amp;rsquo;t get tickets.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 He nods and lets the words pass through either ear.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Do you think you can change it?&amp;rdquo; He asks.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;The past.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re still talking about that? Well, no. That&amp;rsquo;s part of it. Can&amp;rsquo;t change what&amp;rsquo;s already taken place. We have a word for it; it&amp;rsquo;s called history. Now finish your drink.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 My pops stares into his glass like a crystal ball, then finishes what&amp;rsquo;s inside. &lt;br /&gt;
 I pour him another.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Yeah, I figured as much. It&amp;rsquo;s just after my father passed that meant I was next in line. The world looks a lot different once you&amp;rsquo;re forced to look at it that way. You wish you could have made better choices, said certain things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;We all do. It&amp;rsquo;s the ninth inning, pops.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;I know I can&amp;rsquo;t change a thing. I know that. It&amp;rsquo;s just sometimes I wish I could. Is that bad? I mean, I know it&amp;rsquo;s impossible, but people are wishing for impossible things all the time aren&amp;rsquo;t they?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Not me. I&amp;rsquo;m going to live forever. You and me both. Cheers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 We touch glasses, and swallow what&amp;rsquo;s inside. &lt;br /&gt;
When you&amp;rsquo;re Irish you learn not to wince. &lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Hey kid,&amp;rdquo; He says.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Yeah?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;I like watching these games with you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s it,&amp;rdquo; I say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m cutting you off.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 We watch the rest of the game without saying a word.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The next day I flew coach back to my studio apartment in Illinois. I was going to school at the University of Chicago at the time. I waited tables, consumed shameful amounts alcohol and ingested of a wide array of chemicals. For a while life was more or less one long hangover.&lt;br /&gt;
The following spring I received a call from my mother who told me that my dad was driving home from work when he guided his car into the oncoming lane, and then the center divider at 70 miles per hour. I caught a plane back to Boston early the following morning.&lt;br /&gt;
Up until that point Alzheimers was just a name to me. A harrowing abstract idea of an illness whose claim to fame was memory loss. That was where my knowledge began and ended. I understood what it meant on an intellectual level, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone who hasn&amp;rsquo;t experienced it could be prepared to handle it on an emotional one. &lt;br /&gt;
What I learned about Alzheimer's is that it starts with the small things. Short term lapses in memory that happen to all of us, but on a much more frequent basis. His phone, keys, wallet, and other small, but important items were lost with increasing frequency. He&amp;rsquo;d forget the day of the week or show up to work on holidays. I stayed in Boston as long as I could, but once school started up again it was necessary for me to leave.&lt;br /&gt;
 I said goodbye to my father, and then said goodbye to him again.&lt;br /&gt;
When I returned to Chicago I was in a constant state of psychic pain that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t express to anyone. There was guilt associated with leaving my mom alone with him. When someone you love gets sick there&amp;rsquo;s a naive part of you that believes there must be a magic pill to make it all better. And of course, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t. So I dealt with the pain the only way I knew how: I drank. When that didn&amp;rsquo;t work, I tried dulling it with magic pills.&lt;br /&gt;
Almost an entire season passed before I made it back to Massachusetts. My mom had it bad in my absence. Taking care of my dad had turned into a full time job. She worked long hours and weekends. She looked older, more disengaged, but she was happy to have me home, and perhaps even happier to have someone to share the responsibilities of caring for my father with. &lt;br /&gt;
She brought me inside to introduce me to my dad. &lt;br /&gt;
The Alzheimer's had seized his brain like the venom of a poisonous snake. It spread its toxins in lethal doses and launched the armadas of his brain against him. Every day was a clone of the day before. It drove me mad. The routine of it all, living each day with this man who raised me and didn&amp;rsquo;t know my name. We hadn&amp;rsquo;t lost him, but it felt like we had. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t or didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to handle it. And so I drank. I then I drank some more.&lt;br /&gt;
As the disease progressed, so did my father&amp;rsquo;s more reclusive tendencies. My grandfather was an inventor or sorts, and he passed this trait on to his son. My dad would spend hours in his office tinkering with different projects that he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t allow anyone to see, and because we saw it as a productive way to spend his time we didn&amp;rsquo;t ask any questions. &lt;br /&gt;
I left again, and stayed up north until it was time to come back for the holidays. By that point he was unrecognizable. Watching him was like watching a defective, Irish robot do a really bad impersonation of what he used to be like. No part of him was the same. &lt;br /&gt;
On Christmas we talked him into joining us for dinner. Parts of it weren&amp;rsquo;t so bad. There were even fragments of moments where he almost seemed like himself. &lt;br /&gt;
 At night, I watched the snow fall out my old bedroom window. There was something hypnotic about it. I like the snow and the change in season it represents. It reminds me of Christmas as a child. Waking my parents up early to open presents, checking stockings, and inspecting a plate with the crumbs of cookies my Dad had devoured in the name of Santa Claus.&lt;br /&gt;
Inside was warm, and I liked that too. There&amp;rsquo;s a strange sense of comfort that accompanies feeling the opposite of whatever the weather tells you you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be feeling. &lt;br /&gt;
 Covers were ripped away from my body. The curtains were split open flooding the room with the radiant light. &lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Get up. Now!&amp;rdquo; My mother said. &lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;What are you doing?&amp;rdquo; I asked rubbing sleep from my eyes. I glanced at a clock that read: 5:45 am.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Your father. He&amp;rsquo;s gone.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Gone? What do you mean gone? Have you checked the backyard?&amp;rdquo; I rolled out of bed, and slipped into yesterday&amp;rsquo;s pants. &lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Of course I checked the backyard. Get your coat and meet me outside,&amp;rdquo; she said before bolting out the front door. I gathered my coat and followed her out. &lt;br /&gt;
 We searched for hours, scouring the city for any trace of him. My mom remained optimistic and made desperate phone calls to friends to enlist their help. I prayed to be wrong. &lt;br /&gt;
 Our search came to an end when we received a call from Tufts Medical Center. They told us that he had arrived there in an ambulance. Someone had called 911 and reported a half frozen man wandering around the Boston Commons in his pajamas. The same man would die of hypothermia before we could make it to the hospital. The nurse who had tended to him would later explain to us that he was out there looking for his son. &lt;br /&gt;
On the day of his funeral it was cold. I said some words, we buried him beneath an Alder tree, and then we all went home. And that&amp;rsquo;s all I really want to say about the matter. &lt;br /&gt;
 I stuck around for a couple weeks into the spring semester, because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to leave my mother alone. Even though, to some degree, she had seen it coming, she wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared for everything to happen in the way that it did. He had no will, so I helped her disperse what few things he had to the few people he cared about. We cleaned out his closet and his things from the garage. All that was left was what remained in the office, which was, of course, the most difficult room to clean because it was the only room that belonged strictly to him. To us, cleaning it meant admitting that he was gone, and my mom and I just weren&amp;rsquo;t ready to come to terms with the reality of life without him.&lt;br /&gt;
 Inside the office could only be described as immaculately organized chaos. The walls of the room were concealed by layers of handwritten notes. Leaning towers of notebooks were stacked into fragile columns that leaned against each other to stay upright. Polaroid photographs hung from thumb tacks pinned to the drywall, with names scribbled under the portraits in bright red marker. His office had been remodeled into a museum of memories he didn&amp;rsquo;t know belonged to him. &lt;br /&gt;
 Everything was organized in a curved square around a single invention at the center of the room: a chair that looked like the bastard child of a recliner and a torture device. A coil in the back of the chair funneled into a brass headpiece that hovered over the seat. Heart monitors that dangled from the helmet like Christmas ornaments were plugged into a pair of silver goggles. It was ominous, and yet there was something about it at that called to be explored. &lt;br /&gt;
 I went downstairs and had myself a drink. And then I had another, before deciding to take the bottle with me. &lt;br /&gt;
 The leather had been made delicate from years of use. It was weathered and soft, and it contoured to the shape of my figure as I reclined into the seat. The bottle called to me to be poured, and I answered accordingly. &lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;This one&amp;rsquo;s for you,&amp;rdquo; I said, maybe to no one. It went down smooth. &lt;br /&gt;
 The apparatus loomed over me. I pulled it down, and felt it swallow my head. My fingers worked the buttons of my shirt open and attached the heart monitors. The goggles squeezed my temples. &lt;br /&gt;
 I sat and waited for a long time. Waited for nothing to happen. &lt;br /&gt;
 I let my thoughts wander back to a time I can barely remember.&lt;br /&gt;
Ten flaming candles in a cake tell you it&amp;rsquo;s a special kind of day. Wax drips and slithers in neon pink and green spheres down the face of the candle forming translucent puddles where the wick plunges down into the cake. Children form a loose wheel around the table. Juveniles, mostly boys, the same age as me. They sing, with smiles full of holes, a song so obvious it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be named. &lt;br /&gt;
 Mom places the cake down in front of me, the boy at the head of the table. She says make a wish. I close my eyes and wish for superpowers. When I blow out the candles, I spit more than I blow. My mom leans over a corner of the table and cuts the cake into a grid. She&amp;rsquo;s here. Right now before me. Wisps of renegade hair from the edges of her temples stretch away from her skull, and float motionless in time. I breathe in and can smell the floral scent of her perfume braiding with the warm stale smell of bodies packed in a crowded room. &lt;br /&gt;
 A small itch forms on the bridge of my nose, and I use a nail to scratch it. I consider my hand. Feel the weight of my own body. A rush of consciousness, a sudden snap back to reality in that same instantaneous surge of energy you experience after falling asleep while sitting up a bit too straight. Breathing becomes manual. My tongue feels too big for my mouth.&lt;br /&gt;
I see it. &lt;br /&gt;
 There. Hanging in the air, arriving on a granite colored ribbon that withers in the breeze, the scent of burning hay. I follow its jet stream out into the living room. There&amp;rsquo;s a woman on the couch with deep cracks in her skin who looks like she&amp;rsquo;s been there since the dawn of creation. Beside her are men. Hairy men. Fathers equipped with swollen bellies, cherried cigarettes, dirty jeans and running shoes. They sip black ale in clear glasses, nurse smokes, and look over their shoulders before saying words like fuck.&lt;br /&gt;
 At the edge of the sofa I see my father. He does not participate in the gossip. His attention belongs to the television. A navy cap stitched with a pair of twin red and white socks rests on his head. He cheers faithfully in silence. &lt;br /&gt;
 A young boy, who I recognize as myself, rushes up to the man and commits the cardinal sin of telling someone his birthday wish. My dad laughs, removes his cap, and places it on the kid&amp;rsquo;s head.&lt;br /&gt;
 &amp;ldquo;Come with me,&amp;rdquo; He says.&lt;br /&gt;
 We follow our father down the hall. &lt;br /&gt;
 On the walls are sepia toned photos. Captured moments. Relics of a forgotten place in time. My dad pushes over the door and leads me into his bedroom. &lt;br /&gt;
 My 10-year-old self sits on the edge of the bed. His feet swing off the sides and dangle above the carpet like fragile necklaces. &lt;br /&gt;
 I kneel down in front of myself, stare into his eyes and long to trade places. To be invited back into his secret world. His reality, a vaguely familiar dreamstate called childhood where problems are solvable and a sense of purpose and meaning are insignificant. &lt;br /&gt;
I want to linger here forever.&lt;br /&gt;
What I want, is to live infinitely in beautiful moments.&lt;br /&gt;
My dad launches clothes and the misplaced contents of his closet into the air as he excavates his wardrobe until he finds the treasure: An ancient bottle of Irish scotch. &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Here we go,&amp;rdquo; he says. He calls him kid, then tells him to get two glasses. He says if my mom asks he has his permission to lie. &lt;br /&gt;
The kid leaves the room and returns with the glasses. My dad pours a half inch pool in each glass. Swirls it. Inhales the aroma. Without words he instruct the kid to do the same.&lt;br /&gt;
I watch my younger me twirl the glass, and breathe in what&amp;rsquo;s inside. What he smells I smell. A harsh scent of smoked vanilla roasted inside of a barrel. Even then, it reminded me of home. &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Happy birthday, kid. One day you&amp;rsquo;ll be as old as me,&amp;rdquo; He says. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re probably, not ready for this, but I sure as hell am. Been counting down the days since you were born.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
The kid smells the drink again. My dad and I smile. The kid winces.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;I just figure if it&amp;rsquo;s gotta happen at some point, might as well happen with me first.&amp;rdquo; He lowers it to the kid. Remnants of the drink, a liquid tree sap, cling to the walls of the glass, and cascade down to the base of the drink. They touch glasses and before disposing of the liquid inside he stops.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Son,&amp;rdquo; He says. &amp;ldquo;Please. Be better than me, okay?&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;
They drink. The fluid becomes a liquid fire, scorching it&amp;rsquo;s way down inside of me.&lt;br /&gt;
The kid shudders. He tries to act tough and almost succeeds.&lt;br /&gt;
My dad laughs. &lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Go get a coke.&amp;rdquo; He says, and pats him off towards the kitchen.&lt;br /&gt;
The kid leaves. We both watch him go.&lt;br /&gt;
My dad lowers himself to the bed. Fingers spread apart, and pincer back together working to wipe away something in the corner of his eyes. &lt;br /&gt;
I miss him. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things you couldn&amp;rsquo;t help if you tried.&lt;br /&gt;
Because even when I don&amp;rsquo;t, I still do. &lt;br /&gt;
Here he is. Both living and dead. Alone and not alone. Where I am now is where I want to be. &lt;br /&gt;
Fingers shrink the space between us. Stretched out, vibrating, tendrils of flesh that creep closer to the fabric of his shirt. &lt;br /&gt;
Closer.&lt;br /&gt;
In him I see a reflection of myself.&lt;br /&gt;
Here. This is eternal. Because whatever happened, happened. &lt;br /&gt;
 There&amp;rsquo;s comfort in surrendering all hope that the past will improve. Because what we choose to love will never be as perfect as we long for it to be. &lt;br /&gt;
A descending sun radiates stripes of light through the blinds forming vague halos on the wall.&lt;br /&gt;
Closer.&lt;br /&gt;
Until I&amp;rsquo;m hovering over him. His hair a tangled forest of salt and pepper vines. My body follows my arms, lunging forward, closer to the man who put me here, as I attempt to draw him in for a final embrace. &lt;br /&gt;
Closer.&lt;br /&gt;
 Lungs vacuumed air back into my lungs. I collapsed from the chair, soaked in sweat, a drowning man choking in air. &lt;br /&gt;
 I&amp;rsquo;m here. Back to where I was.&lt;br /&gt;
 Back to where you are.&lt;br /&gt;
 I dust myself off. Listen to the sound of my heart beating.. &lt;br /&gt;
 I consider my hand. Feel the weight of my own body. &lt;br /&gt;
 The bottle calls to me, and I answer accordingly. I sink back into the chair, and let my mind wander back to a place I barely remember. &lt;br /&gt;
Right now I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in my father&amp;rsquo;s office thinking on memory I can barely remember. The calendar reads August 17th, 2012, and my mother is away on vacation. There&amp;rsquo;s a faint hum of passing cars as they drift off into the night to unknown destinations. The illumination of the television is the only light our world. A sportscaster informs us that the Red Sox lead the Cubs by two runs, here, at the bottom of the eighth. We sip scotch on the rocks and smoke indoors. I mirror his posture. Shoes on, feet kicked up resting on the coffee table we kiss flaming cigarettes, and let thoughts wander to the rhythm of the game. Here time is irrelevant. Everything and nothing is temporary. Spectral streams of smoke twist and bend in the light as they dissolve into thin clouds making us appear as ghosts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Camp Paradise</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/171114-Camp-Paradise</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <author></author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From the time I entered third grade until I graduated the eighth, I spent a week out of every summer at a church camp named Camp Paradise. The program was set up in such a way that our parents would pay like $200 and some sucker, who was generally one of our dads, and some teenager they convinced to volunteer, would have to babysit a bunch of other people&amp;rsquo;s maniac children for an entire week. The campers&amp;rsquo; ages ranged from eight to thirteen, and the crew consisted of a collection of church kids&amp;#9135;&amp;#9135;from a wide variety of sheltered homes&amp;#9135;&amp;#9135;many of whom were being given a taste of freedom for the first time in their lives. Some of us capitalized on the newfound freedom, while others abused it. &lt;br /&gt;
 The exploitation of freedom manifested itself most commonly in our dietary choices for the week. This began the moment we boarded the bus. Each camper was given about $20 for food on the way up and back, as well as a small supply of snacks; our mothers had enough faith in us to think that we would portion out what we were given. We ate almost all of the snacks before we left the city, and then after about an hour of driving, in the name of road trip traditions, we stopped and consumed about a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of fast food before we continued onwards to Paradise. &lt;br /&gt;
 It was our first time going to the fabled camp. We had never seen it for ourselves. We crafted images in our heads based on what the older kids had told us about Paradise, and we imagined it as advertised. A weekend getaway with all of our buddies where we would do nothing but goof off and make jokes at each other&amp;rsquo;s expense. I envisioned myself exiting the bus and stepping into a Protestant Wonderland. In my head Camp Paradise was an outdoor version of Disneyland with a lot more Jesus, and maybe the occasional worship song&amp;#9135;&amp;#9135;led by some teenager in a v-neck&amp;#9135;&amp;#9135;that I&amp;rsquo;d have to learn a couple of hand motions for. Instead, I was greeted with a dystopian landscape that resembled a refugee camp for children.&lt;br /&gt;
 Most of the property was barren, and the parts that weren&amp;rsquo;t probably should have been. When my friends had described Paradise to me I envisioned a camp grounds modeled after the Wonka Factory. Instead I was greeted with a combination of buildings crafted out of what seemed to be cardboard and rusty metal. The recreational areas looked more dangerous than fun, and the expansive forest that circled the ground from every angle permeated that very specific you-couldn&amp;rsquo;t-leave-here-if-you-wanted to feeling. It looked like the setting for a low budget slasher film&amp;#9135;&amp;#9135;but worse. &lt;br /&gt;
 Once we arrived, the first objective was to get us settled into the cabin. This proved difficult for our counselors, J.R. and his teenage companion, Gilbert, because it meant wrangling together 12 kids, who all but perspiring sugar and had been held in captivity for hours. We were animals, and yet they managed to tame us long enough to get us to gather our bags and march us exiles up to the cabin we would be staying in for the week. &lt;br /&gt;
 The origins of the cabin could probably be traced back to the late Cretaceous period. Prior to being allowed inside, we were given a pep talk on what to do if we were bitten by poisonous spiders and snakes that could be (and were) located inside the cabin. The windows consisted of large wooden rectangles that were propped open with a long board that allowed some heat to escape, but also welcomed any pests that desired to come inside, as if they were family. The bunk beds were organized in a chain that left just a sliver of floor space. The bathrooms and the bushes out the back door were synonymous, and the temperature inside was not unlike a sauna. I grabbed one of the bottom bunks, and shoved my things underneath my bed while others claimed their own stretch of land for the week. By the time we had set up a headquarters at the cabin it was time for dinner, so we made our way to the mess hall for our first dinner in Paradise. &lt;br /&gt;
 The first dinner served was chicken, and I remember there being some drama involved with the dish. What had happened was that the chefs, who were probably unpaid volunteers, had not cooked the chicken properly. And by properly, I mean the chicken was not cooked. Unfortunately this was brought to their attention after dinner had already been served, and the kitchen staff went scrambling from table to table, in a frenzy, alerting the kids that they should, under no circumstances, eat the food that they had already eaten. We were given a short speech on the symptoms of E. Coli, and what to do if we felt we were experiencing these symptoms, and then we were carted off to chapel like the Jews fleeing Egypt.&lt;br /&gt;
 Chapel was a spectacle. Every. Time. There were two services a day, and each one was a three hour long emotional rollercoaster. The services began with worship, and then rapidly descended into madness when a particularly veiny bald pastor seized the microphone. The guy was always damp with sweat and intense in real puritan kind of way, and there was never any emotional buffer between his message and the worship. It was as if he had been backstage listening to Eminem all day, and was finally getting the chance to channel all of the pent up rage onto his juvenile audience. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the specifics of what he talked about, but I do remember the flaring passion in which he talked about them and the tendency he had for speaking in tongues mid-sentence. Under normal circumstances this would have been fine, because children are hardwired to daydream whenever they&amp;rsquo;re forced to listen to anything uninteresting. However these were not normal circumstances.&lt;br /&gt;
 To complicate matters, the chapel had a horde of bats living within the rafters that fluttered around during the service, often swooping down to remind us of their presence. Subconsciously, I think we were all supportive of anything to take our minds off of the bald man&amp;rsquo;s verbal onslaught, but the bats wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been our first choice of distraction. We were informed that we were not to worry about the flying vampiric rats with sonar vision, and that bats were practically harmless to humans. However, we were told that if we were bitten or made any kind of physical contact with said bats we would not turn into vampires, but rather would need to get a massive shot plunged into our ass to prevent us from dying a horrible death via rabies. &lt;br /&gt;
Chapel eventually came to a close, and I thanked the Lord that it was over. Afterwards, we were given a couple hours of free time to explore and do whatever we wanted around camp.&lt;br /&gt;
 Camp Paradise offered very few amenities, but one thing they did offer was a snack shack. Each camper was granted $5 of store credit to be used as we saw fit. All of us, unanimously, saw it fit to go bankrupt the first night in what must have been a competition to see who could get the most cavities by the end of the week. It was apocalyptic. Walking no longer existed. Campers sprinted to their freetime destinations, climbing on whatever and whoever they could, and funneling sugar into their bodies like it was the antidote to a venomous disease. I was no exception and am not proud of the fact that I consumed no fewer than 4 Nerds Ropes within a single hour. At one point, I witnessed with my own eyes one kid sprint out of the snack shack and proclaim &amp;ldquo;I AM DRUNK OFF SUGAR,&amp;rdquo; before dumping an entire bottle of Coca-Cola over his own head. &lt;br /&gt;
Now the counselors did their best, but they weren&amp;rsquo;t our parents, and there were simply too many of us to monitor our behavior. Their approach was to treat us like a wildfire and just let us burn out eventually. They watched the riot unfold from the comfort of picnic tables set up on the deck extending from the mess hall. They sipped water they probably wished were beers and were generally amused by the chaos. &lt;br /&gt;
 At the end of the night we ended up back in our cabin. We curled up in our sleeping bags and listened to scary stories told by the older campers in what was epitome of what you imagine when you think of camp. It was like living in a postcard. The older boys were orators passing down a tradition of telling stories about murders, serial killers, and ghosts. And there we were, lying in bed while the mosquitoes ate us alive. &lt;br /&gt;
 Up until this point camp was far from what I had imagined prior to arrival. No one had warned me about the quality of the food, the borderline traumatizing chapels, or the encampmentesque living conditions. But lying in bed at night, trading stories, and bonding over our shared fears somehow felt like vacation we had been expecting. This was the camp we envisioned in our heads. But underneath there were dark forces lurking. The generally healthy diets we enjoyed at home had been thrown a massive curveball in the form of a year's worth of fat and sugar consumed in a matter of hours. This, combined with an entire meal&amp;rsquo;s worth of uncooked chicken, spelled out a disastrous future that we felt, but we were just beginning to understand. The room fell into a tense, pregnant silence. The counselors, in a sort of na&amp;iuml;ve form of optimism, must have imagined that we were beginning to fall asleep. &lt;br /&gt;
 Nate, who is to this day one of my best friends, was the first victim. He rose from his bag, his eyes pinched tightly together as he gripped his stomach. He complained about the bag of Doritos he had just eaten, and expelled what must have been half of his own body weight through his mouth. It built up like water pressing against a dam and overflowed onto the campers bed beneath him. And then suddenly, all at once, he was not alone. One by one we began to erupt. All over the cabin, an entire week&amp;rsquo;s worth of snack shack store credit was released in a symphony of body fluids. In a strange way it was kind of beautiful. The unity of it all. Here we were, undivided, spilling our guts before God. &lt;br /&gt;
 Within minutes we were all participating in the festivities, everyone except Nate&amp;rsquo;s brother Chase who seemed to be enjoying the madness. But Chase&amp;rsquo;s laughs were made silent once it was clear he was about to become part of our crew. Gilbert, the teenager, in a bizarre act of heroism took action and rushed to Chase&amp;rsquo;s aid. He charged across the room, and plucked him from his bed. Chase was hoisted up by his armpits, and escorted towards the door to evacuate his stomach into our &amp;ldquo;bathroom.&amp;rdquo; They almost made it. I imagine that facing Chase towards him instead of away is still one of Gilbert&amp;rsquo;s biggest regrets in life. &lt;br /&gt;
 As fate would have it, almost a decade later I would discover some of the more unflattering side effects of alcohol with the same people I shared the cabin with. There was a period where Saturdays were consumed with fighting over porcelain thrones to bury our heads in, and Sundays were spent waking up post-rager face in the very same position.&lt;br /&gt;
 A typical day at Camp Paradise looked like this: Wake up. Skip brushing your teeth. Breakfast. Painfully long chapel. Lunch. Games and activities. Dinner. A second equally painful chapel. Activity. Bed. Now the games portion sounds like fun until you actually have to participate in playing them. More often than not they were either dangerous, or were chores disguised as games. Sometimes they were both. A prime example of that sweet spot in the middle is a game we played called Roll the Logs. In this particular game the objective was to take an enormous log and literally roll it off of a basketball court behind the chapel as fast as we could. The logs were tall and wide, and as a result it took an entire cabin to move a single one. In the first round I watched one of the older guys get vaulted over the log by the sheer momentum of the tree and almost get flattened beneath it. After that, here was a brief discussion on whether or not the game was safe to play. The elected jury ultimately ruled in favor of the games safety, and then in an event that should have surprised no one, I watched one of the girls who rode up with us get the nail ripped off her big toe by the tumbling tree in the following round. Most of the time we needed to be all but held back from participating in anything that would have put our lives at risk, but when it came to Roll the Logs, I think we would have all been okay with leaving the logs unrolled. &lt;br /&gt;
 Sometimes the activities we participated in were ones we actually liked. Campfires were events we looked forward to. We enjoyed the archery course and shooting paintball guns at far away cardboard targets. There was a basketball court, where I frequently embarrassed myself, and there was also a place in the sand to play tetherball where some kid from another church called me a &amp;ldquo;faggot&amp;rdquo; for the first (of many) time in my life. &lt;br /&gt;
Parts of the stay were pleasant, but the parts that weren&amp;rsquo;t were viewed as speed bumps in a smooth ride. We were California city boys spoiled by years of air conditioning and mothers that applied sunscreen to our bodies against our will. Every day was a scorcher that was magnified by the conscientious rejection of all things that protected us from burns. Because it was so hot, and there was no other way to cool down, nearly everyone&amp;rsquo;s favorite activity was swimming in the pool. &lt;br /&gt;
When at the pool, you had to be on your toes at all times. Literally. Because if you walked around flat footed that dramatically increased the chances of stepping on something you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to step on. My first day at the pool I stepped on a rusty piece of metal that made me thankful that getting a tetanus shot was a requirement before coming to camp. When I asked J.R. what I should do about my leaking foot he took me the first aid where they gave me a band-aid, and no antiseptic.&lt;br /&gt;
 Pool time was segregated. Always. There was the boy&amp;rsquo;s pool time and the girl&amp;rsquo;s pool time, and the two never overlapped. When explaining the camp rules, they had this saying they used to sling at us right out of the gate that went something like: Boys are blue. Girls are pink. And you don&amp;rsquo;t make purple. The older we got, the more difficult it became not to break the purple rule, but at the time, as nine year old boys, it was great. Having a pool to ourselves meant that we could be as rough with each other as we wanted without hurting anyone that we didn&amp;rsquo;t mean to. No matter how civil things started, they always transformed into some kind of warfare. Whether it was between counselors and campers, or church against church we found a way to keep things competitive and borderline Old Testament.&lt;br /&gt;
 Out of all the adventures camp had to offer there was one that ranked far above the rest. It was without a doubt, the most highly anticipated and celebrated event camp had to offer. A tradition passed on from generation to generation. The main event. The cr&amp;eacute;me de la cr&amp;eacute;me of our camp experience: The Raid of the Kitchen. &lt;br /&gt;
 Raiding the kitchen was a rite of passage that was meticulously planned by us campers with the help of our counselors in which we broke into the kitchen and stole all of the leftover food. If we were caught, the penalty was to be sent home early. We knew the risks, and we were willing to face the consequences. J.R. was known as the John Rambo of kitchen raids. He had coordinated over a dozen over the years and he had never lost a man. He drew up a plan, and we placed our lives in his hands. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t your run in the mill rule-breaking; this was an operation. Flashlights were banned. We wore all black pants and long-sleeved black shirts. I even brought eye black that we smoothed over our faces like obsidian makeup. &lt;br /&gt;
Camp Paradise was built on a mountain surrounded by towering evergreen trees with low hanging branches. The key to a successful raid was to stay low and move under the protection of the pines until you were close enough to the kitchen to try and sprint inside. Now the kitchen was far from Fort Knox, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t without its security measures. For one, the doors had alarms on them that seemed to signal the end of the world if they went off. The second obstacle was the guards. Because they had had the kitchen raided so many times in the past, they decided to have counselors act as sentries patrolling the interior of the building for any intruder who might wander in in search of poisonous food. This proved to be a much more difficult obstacle to overcome. Luckily we had an inside man. &lt;br /&gt;
Gilbert had been selected as a guard this particular night, and he acted as a double agent sabotaging the defenses of the kitchen from the inside. It was up to him to distract the other guard just long enough for us to get in and take what we needed. The plan was bulletproof. The mission was over before it began. In our minds, we just needed to do the legwork.&lt;br /&gt;
And so it began. We hiked down from our cabins to the foot of the hill, and began sprinting, one at a time, to a tree line that ran parallel to the mess hall. Our feet glided over the pine needles as we moved with the shadows to a point right beside the building. Gilbert was in the window. He flashed a light twice to signify that the coast was clear. J.R. led the charge towards the stairs that lead up to the front of the kitchen and peeled the door open. He held it and signaled us to be quiet as the rest of us boys funneled inside. &lt;br /&gt;
 We were led into a kitchen where the food was laid out like a buffet. It was organized. Split into sections and categorized by meat, carbs, fruit, vegetables, and dessert. The food that needed to be refrigerated was still cold. The whole spread was immaculate, far better than it ever looked when it was being served. It was perfect. A set up intended for us. &lt;br /&gt;
Because it was. &lt;br /&gt;
All of it. &lt;br /&gt;
The all black outfits, the eye black, the lack of flashlights, the alarms, the guards, the sneaking around; it was all part of a grand illusion. The raid had been a carefully orchestrated charade, planned and invented by the counselors in the same spirit in which they had told their kids about Santa Claus. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t malicious. In fact, it was quite the opposite. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t let a bunch of elementary school kids sneak out of their cabins in the middle of the night to steal camp food, but part of them remembered what it was like to be a kid, so they invented a way that we still could. &lt;br /&gt;
Perspective can be a confusing bitch some of the time. It&amp;rsquo;s what responsible for making time feel like it&amp;rsquo;s both fast and slow at once. It&amp;rsquo;s what forces you to consider every heart you never broke, and it&amp;rsquo;s at the heart of every apathetic moment you have alone in your bed when you think about the opportunities that slipped through your fingers simply because you were unaware that they existed. But it&amp;rsquo;s not all bad. Because it can&amp;rsquo;t be. &lt;br /&gt;
When I reflect back on my summers spent at Paradise, it comes from the perspective of someone straddling the gap in age between the junior and senior counselors. The most important question for me is why anyone with a sound mind would be willing to spend a week&amp;rsquo;s worth of vacation days babysitting. For one, someone had to. Sure. But suppose this is only half of the answer. Suppose they came because part of them wanted to. Because maybe they identified part of themselves in these stupid, sunburned kids; a part of them that may have been buried but not lost. Perspective can be a confusing bitch some of the time, but certainly not all of the time. When you&amp;rsquo;re a kid, everything happens in the present tense. And there&amp;rsquo;s a certain contagious charm that comes with being around people who are truly content with simply existing. Raiding the kitchen wasn&amp;rsquo;t about the food. It was about being a child, taking chances, and enjoying life without any reservations. &lt;br /&gt;
At camp we were given the opportunity to determine our own vacation. We consumed enough junk food to intoxicate a small army, we shot paintballs at cardboard, scuffled in pools, and ransacked kitchens for food we didn&amp;rsquo;t want, and we loved it. &lt;br /&gt;
On the last day of camp we packed up and loaded our things into the bus. We had been there for five days, but it had seemed like a year. I won&amp;rsquo;t say that we wished we could have stayed there forever, because we didn&amp;rsquo;t. We wanted to go home. We missed our parents, and our beds, and showers, and meals that were approved by the FDA, but we also knew we would be back the following year. And the next summer we returned a little bit closer to the people we would become. We were older and perhaps a little less naive. Mosquitoes and bats still taunted us with fear of disease. There had been no improvements made to any of the facilities, and the food was still as dangerous as the previous year. The camp was largely unchanged, and was still the same dilapidated, decrepit campgrounds it had been the year before. But we were kids there to be kids, and to us, it resembled paradise. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    

  </channel>
</rss>
